Hi folks, welcome back live stream
Reacton 2025 day two. I'm here with Mike
Robavski, CTO and founder of Call Stack.
Hello.
>> Hey Mike, how you doing?
>> Great. Thanks for having me here.
>> Yeah, thank you for being here and
answering the questions from our live
studio uh live studio from our live
audience. Um and let's get started.
Okay,
>> let's go.
>> Cool. How lightweight is React Native
brownfield? Does it significantly
increase bundle size? That's a very good
question uh because you won't believe me
but I have never actually profiled the
actual u bundle size impact of the
brownfield library itself but I wouldn't
call it significant just because it is
mostly a couple of native files that I
would treat as helpers and utilities. So
generally speaking considering the whole
react native and all the native modules
you're adding to your application that
shouldn't feel like anything
significant.
>> Okay. Okay. Um, what kind of migration
path do you hope teams take? Start
small, one screen or feature islands? Do
you have any recommendations?
>> Typically, where we see most people uh
success stories is around starting with
uh a single screen and then uh gradually
moving outside. I mean that really
depends on your organization how you set
yourself KPIs, but it's either a screen
or feature island depending on that
migration.
>> Okay, cool. And speaking of migration
and success stories, are there any
brownfield success stories you can share
with us?
>> Yeah, there is a lot of I mean
unfortunately there's quite a few NDAs
I've signed over time. However, um you
know, we've seen um we've seen during
the keynote in the morning, we've seen
Zando and HelloFresh being showcased for
their brownfield stories and um React
Native Brownfield is pretty much um well
there is a picture of brownfield library
in uh one of the articles. So that's
what that one is easy to figure out. But
one thing to keep in mind is that
reactive brownfield itself is not a uh
it's not just a library. It's more of an
approach. You can really do it without
using our library. It's more about how
you package it. So I would say uh if you
look at those two articles uh they
pretty much uh capture reactive
brownfield and I would think of these
two as success story.
>> Okay. Wonderful. And how does the final
state of apps using brownfield look
like? Is it more of a hybrid approach or
do they fully transfer to React Native
over time?
>> Also very good question. I think often a
um misconception is that you have to
finish at a green field stage. So you
have to finish the rewrite uh where we
see a lot of companies being successful
is starting the migration uh doing only
the things that are necessary. Sometimes
they end up being grafield for the
foreseeable future. So I would say when
you start using uh React Native inside
your mobile app, do not aim necessarily
for phasing out all of your native
screens, if you end up staying somewhere
in between, that's perfectly fine.
>> Yeah. Cool. Well, thank you for sharing
those insights on migration and uh two
final questions for you. What's your
favorite React feature of all times?
>> Honestly, I love uh Hooks.
>> Okay. Wow.
>> I like Hooks. I I like how they u
initially when I was switching from
classes they made me change my mental
model and I learned a lot while I was
shifting from classes to function
components.
>> Okay. And what's uh what's a thing about
you that doesn't come up in normal
conversation.
>> So see here's the thing every time I go
to a conference I try to be uh very
lowkey about everything I do outside. I
mostly focus on code and I'm always
fully locked in. Okay.
>> But my passion is cars. I love driving.
style of racing and um
>> thing to know about me is that I have
full sleeve tattoo here and it's my
first car BMW. I have it tattooed all
the pieces on my arm. I cannot show it
right here but maybe when we meet the
other day you'll see it right here.
>> Part of the suspension is right here. So
it's like this little passion of mine.
>> Really passionate.
>> Yeah.
>> Cool. I never realized you had a full
sleeve. That's really cool.
>> Uh it was supposed to be a mystery so I
didn't really answer the question. Yeah.
There you go.
>> Thank you so much, Mike, for joining us
today. And uh folks, stay tuned.